<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bookdown | Anh Hoang Duc</title>
    <link>http://anhhoangduc.com/tag/bookdown/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://anhhoangduc.com/tag/bookdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>bookdown</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017 Anh Hoang Duc</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://anhhoangduc.com/images/icon_hu2b6525e60a3fd142ceb00d0e8ef368f7_181234_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>bookdown</title>
      <link>http://anhhoangduc.com/tag/bookdown/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a book with bookdown in foreign languages</title>
      <link>http://anhhoangduc.com/post/writing-a-book-with-bookdown-in-foreign-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://anhhoangduc.com/post/writing-a-book-with-bookdown-in-foreign-languages/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I remember 4 years back when I started writing master thesis in &lt;code&gt;Warsaw School of Economics&lt;/code&gt;, I started to learn &lt;code&gt;LaTeX&lt;/code&gt; and it was an amazing tool to write technical documents. However, to master &lt;code&gt;LaTeX&lt;/code&gt; is not an easy job at all as it is quite tricky to solve various problems. To tell you the truth, since then I never ever used LateX again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When started using &lt;code&gt;Rmarkdown&lt;/code&gt; in 2016, it was very clear to me that &lt;code&gt;Rmarkdown&lt;/code&gt; would be my favarite language to write any technical and non-technical documents. Since 2016, many new packages in &lt;code&gt;markdown&lt;/code&gt; family have been borned and has helped statisticians, analysts around the world to write better &amp;amp; easier. For blogging, we have fantastic &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; (my 2 websites are written in blogdown). However, I haven’t tried using &lt;code&gt;bookdown&lt;/code&gt; yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I would like to write a book about practical data science with my experience and knowledge in Vietnamese, I started to use &lt;code&gt;bookdown&lt;/code&gt; and try to write the book in Vietnamese. It sounds quite easy as there are many fantastic tutorial available online. However, to write a book in foreign language rather than English is not that easy if you do not know LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I want to share some simple but very effective tips to write a book with &lt;code&gt;bookdown&lt;/code&gt; in foreign language in some simple steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-1-install-bookdown&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 1: Install bookdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is the critical part to start to write a book with &lt;code&gt;bookdown&lt;/code&gt;. You can install bookdown easily as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&amp;quot;bookdown&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-2-create-a-new-project-with-bookdown&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 2: Create a new project with bookdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installing bookdown, you can easily create a new &lt;code&gt;book project&lt;/code&gt; with bookdown from &lt;code&gt;RStudio&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;File &amp;gt;&amp;gt; New Project &amp;gt;&amp;gt; New bookproject using bookdown&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing this part, you already have had a standard, simple book to follow (of course, it is in English). So, the next steps are to change the contents into your desired language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-3-read-follow-instruction-from-bookdowns-author&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 3: Read &amp;amp; follow instruction from bookdown’s author&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Yihui&lt;/code&gt; has written a great book about how to use &lt;code&gt;bookdown&lt;/code&gt; efficiently. In this online book, there is a chapter which helps you to internationalize your book, or namely to write a book in other languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do it, you can simply translate all parameters defined in bookdown into your language. The default translation of these parameters are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;language:
  label:
    fig: &amp;#39;Figure &amp;#39;
    tab: &amp;#39;Table &amp;#39;
    eq: &amp;#39;Equation &amp;#39;
    thm: &amp;#39;Theorem &amp;#39;
    lem: &amp;#39;Lemma &amp;#39;
    cor: &amp;#39;Corollary &amp;#39;
    prp: &amp;#39;Proposition &amp;#39;
    cnj: &amp;#39;Conjecture &amp;#39;
    def: &amp;#39;Definition &amp;#39;
    exm: &amp;#39;Example &amp;#39;
    exr: &amp;#39;Exercise &amp;#39;
    proof: &amp;#39;Proof. &amp;#39;
    remark: &amp;#39;Remark. &amp;#39;
    solution: &amp;#39;Solution. &amp;#39;
  ui:
    edit: Edit
    chapter_name: &amp;#39;&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read all details in the following link &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/bookdown/internationalization.html&#34;&gt;https://bookdown.org/yihui/bookdown/internationalization.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after translating above parameters, it works only in HTML version, not &lt;code&gt;pdf&lt;/code&gt; one. I searched through the internet but it could not find any specific instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key thing here is to change the &lt;code&gt;preamble.tex&lt;/code&gt; file in your project. The original &lt;code&gt;preamble&lt;/code&gt; file is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\usepackage{booktabs}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the whole book translated into your desired language, you need to add 2 lines of codes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\usepackage{booktabs}
\usepackage[utf8]{inputenc}
\usepackage[vietnamese]{babel}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your language is &lt;code&gt;spanish&lt;/code&gt;, feel free to change &lt;code&gt;vietnamese&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;spanish&lt;/code&gt;. After changing, your book will work perfectly with all contents, parameters translated into your language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope that this tip could help &lt;code&gt;analysts&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;bookdown&lt;/code&gt; easier when writing a book in their own languages!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
