<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anh Hoang Duc on Anh Hoang Duc</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anh Hoang Duc on Anh Hoang Duc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Anh Hoang Duc</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate marketing effectiveness using web scraping techniques</title>
      <link>/project/marketing-effectiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/marketing-effectiveness/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing department has used service from a vender for email marketing, which was impossible to evaluate the real effect on customers behaviors as well as to get insights of marketing campaigns. The challenge is to be able to evaluate the effectiveness of each campaign to justify accordingly for better campaign&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project team applied data scraping methods in conjunction with Selenium web browser automation tool to extract email marketing data from external outsourced sources. After that, we performed data exploratory analysis to understand which messages were well-received, when customers reacted, and the respond patterns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 5 days of an email campaign’ sending date, Sales and Marketing staff can view conversion rates of that campaign based on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers’ response to the email marketing campaign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their corresponding internet banking behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-impact&#34;&gt;Business Impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estimated time saved from interdepartmental communication and individual report generation is 1248 working hours per year, which could be converted into a save of 150 million VND per year&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyze customer location</title>
      <link>/project/spatial-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/spatial-analytics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operation division wanted optimize ATM &amp;amp; branch location for the bank. The challenge is to identify customers locations to understand how location could affect customers behaviors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve the problem, the team crawed spatial data from Google Maps to identify the longitudes &amp;amp; latitudes of customers and their ATM/branch location when using the bank services. After that, the Operation division were able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the exact location of customer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the distance from a customer to the branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimate the effect of relocating a branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install R packages from Github through proxy</title>
      <link>/post/install-r-packages-from-github-through-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/install-r-packages-from-github-through-proxy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to install an R package is from R-Cran. However, as the number of R users is growing up very fast, many developers are contribute to R community through Github. And the standard way to install from Github is to use &lt;code&gt;devtools&lt;/code&gt; package with &lt;code&gt;install_github()&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many organization, especially financial organization like banking industry, sometimes it is very hard to install an R package from CRAN or Github due to security process. So, in this post I will share with you 2 ways to install an R package via proxy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;method-1-using-downloader-package&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Method 1: Using &lt;code&gt;downloader&lt;/code&gt; package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this method, the only thing that you need to change is the Github repository of the R package needed to be installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you want to install package &lt;code&gt;easyRFM&lt;/code&gt; from Github with the following link: &lt;code&gt;github.com/hoxo-m/easyRFM&lt;/code&gt;, you can easily install with the following codes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#Step 1: Install downloader from CRAN
install.packages(&amp;quot;downloader&amp;quot;)
library(downloader)

#Step 2: Download R package from Github in format .tar.gz
download(&amp;quot;https://github.com/hoxo-m/easyRFM/archive/master.tar.gz&amp;quot;,
         &amp;quot;easyRFM.tar.gz&amp;quot;)

#Step 3: Install from source
install.packages(&amp;quot;easyRFM.tar.gz&amp;quot;, repos = NULL, type = &amp;quot;source&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;method-2-using-httr-package-to-modify-your-proxy&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Method 2: Using &lt;code&gt;httr&lt;/code&gt; package to modify your proxy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this method, you can modify your proxy using &lt;code&gt;httr&lt;/code&gt; package. To modify your proxy, the key function is &lt;code&gt;set_config&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;httr::set_config(use_proxy(&amp;quot;your_proxy:your_port&amp;quot;))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if your proxy is &lt;code&gt;11.36.22.12&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; your port is &lt;code&gt;8080&lt;/code&gt;, you can modify your proxy as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#Step 1: Call httr &amp;amp; devtools
library(httr)
library(devtools)

#Step 2: Modify proxy
set_config(use_proxy(&amp;quot;11.36.22.12:8080&amp;quot;))

#Step 3: Install package directly from Github
install_github(&amp;quot;rstats-db/odbc&amp;quot;)

#Step 4: Reset your proxy if needed
reset_config()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two methods above help me a lot to install R packages, specially from Github. Hope that it will help you also to make your life easier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to manage libraries in R efficiently?</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-manage-libraries-in-r-efficiently/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-manage-libraries-in-r-efficiently/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When starting using with R, installing and managing R libraries seems not to be a difficult task at all. However, when updating R to new version, it will make some problems. For most cases, you have to re-install your library, which takes much time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another tricky way to solve that problem, which is to copy all your old libraries to the new library folder. For example, all your libraries in R version 3.3 are in &lt;code&gt;C:/Program Files/R/R-3.3.0/library&lt;/code&gt;. Now that you update your R version to 3.4.0 but don’t want to install all libraries, an easy way (not the easiest) to do it is to copy all folders from &lt;code&gt;D:\My Documents\R\win-library\3.3&lt;/code&gt; to the new one &lt;code&gt;D:\My Documents\R\win-library\3.4&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this approach has some disadvantages. Firstly, it takes time to copy from old library folder to the new one, some time it takes up to 40~50 minutes when you are using many libraries. Secondly, if you have multiple versions of R, the approach might consume unnecessary couple of Gigabytes in your disk (as libraries are duplicated). Finally, you cannot install libraries once and use it multiple times, for each version of R (for me, &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; from CRAN and &lt;code&gt;Microsoft R&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;R Services&lt;/code&gt;) you have to install (or copy) from each folder to another ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I found a very efficient way that can simplify all theses difficulties above in few easy steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1&lt;/strong&gt;: Create a &lt;em&gt;permanent folder&lt;/em&gt; for your R library in your laptop. For me, I created a folder in &lt;code&gt;D:/Rlibrary&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Copy all folders from your original R library (in my case is &lt;code&gt;D:\My Documents\R\win-library\3.3&lt;/code&gt;) to &lt;code&gt;D:/Rlibrary&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Now, you have to make R understand &lt;code&gt;D:/Rlibrary&lt;/code&gt; (new folder) is your default libraries, all new libraries will be installed to that folder.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open R Studio to find your R library paths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.libPaths()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;D:/Rlibrary&amp;quot;                       
## [2] &amp;quot;C:/Program Files/R/R-3.3.0/library&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will see that I have 2 paths, one is my &lt;code&gt;D:/Rlibrary&lt;/code&gt; - just ignore it &amp;amp; the second one &lt;code&gt;C:/Program Files/R/R-3.3.0/library&lt;/code&gt;. We will change the default library paths as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;C:/Program Files/R/R-3.3.0/library&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to folder &lt;code&gt;base\R&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy file &lt;code&gt;Rprofile&lt;/code&gt; to desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;Rprofile&lt;/code&gt; with text editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the following code in the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;Rprofile&lt;/code&gt; back to &lt;code&gt;C:/Program Files/R/R-3.3.0/library/base/R&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart R studio and when typing &lt;code&gt;.libPaths()&lt;/code&gt;, you will see your default library changed to &lt;code&gt;D:/Rlibrary&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method can be applied to &lt;code&gt;R Server&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;R Services&lt;/code&gt; as well for &lt;code&gt;Microsoft R Server&lt;/code&gt;. For my local server, I changes Rprofile files in following folders:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R Server: &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\Microsoft\R Server\R_SERVER\library\base\R&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R Services: &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\Microsoft SQL Server\MSSQL13.ANHHD\R_SERVICES\library\base\R&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing it, you can see all libraries from all R version, &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; from CRAN, &lt;code&gt;R Server&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;R Service&lt;/code&gt; from Microsoft synchronized! When you install a new library from CRAN, you &lt;code&gt;R Service&lt;/code&gt; from SQLRServer can use it, too! Really fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./img/sqlrserver.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it great! For me, this little trick help me a lot! Hope that you will enjoy it and find it helpful! Let me know if you have any comment!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gcushen.github.io/hugo-academic-demo/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build recommendation engine for VPBank&#39;s customers</title>
      <link>/project/recommendation-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/recommendation-engine/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SMEs division wanted to cross-sell products for each customers. The challenge is to identify suitable products for each customers &amp;amp; transfer the output to sales for deep-farming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applied &lt;em&gt;apriori algorithm&lt;/em&gt; on customer products holding data to develop the recommendation engine. The engine was integrated with Customer 360 and automatically updated every month. For each sale, the engine found customer patterns with the highest probabilities of purchase a given product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-impact&#34;&gt;Business Impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identified next best offer products for all customers for SMEs monthly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased cross selling campain 1.88X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict credit card attritors</title>
      <link>/project/credit-card-attrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/credit-card-attrition/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challange&#34;&gt;The challange&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issueing credit cards is one of the main focuses of VPBank&amp;rsquo;s Retail Division, with a target of multi thousands new cards in 2017. However, there is little meaning in acquiring new card holders if they are going to churn in big numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, attrition rate was very high for newly issued cards, posing a substantial problem.
This calls for a need to identify potential attritors months before they make the action, enabling the Bank to take corrective measures to keep them from churning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The predictive problem belongs to the unbalanced classification category, one of the most difficult predictive models, with the monthly portion of attritors equalling to 2% of that of active cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final model was built using the &lt;strong&gt;Gradient Boosting Machine (GBM)&lt;/strong&gt; method after &lt;strong&gt;tuning multi hyper-parameters&lt;/strong&gt;.
As a combination between gradient descent and ada boost, GBM is a method of machine learning which combines many different decision trees to produce a powerful predictive model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also used data manipulation methods and activity analysis to find insightful findings within the transaction and card information datasets,
as well as build a customer profile that segments our customer base into 4 groups with distinctive between-group demographic and spending behaviors:
&lt;strong&gt;Attritors, High Risk Users, Typical Users and High Frequency Users&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilizing the model in conjuction with the customer profile, the Analytics team was able to provide the Products team with a list of almost &lt;strong&gt;12K potential attritors&lt;/strong&gt; and their respective card closing probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also made data-driven recommendations in regards of card policies, cross-selling programs and marketing campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list was provided for the Products team and is in use for a trial 3-month &amp;ldquo;Happy Call&amp;rdquo; Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also propose many target plan regarding customers&amp;rsquo; transacting behaviours
to maintain them with the bank, for instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The group of users that should be offered other product as the are misusing credit card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific number of tracsaction that each customers should have every one month &amp;amp; two months to make them to be loyal customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model is updated on quarterly basis to be able to detect credit card attritor more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After one year utilizing predictive modelling and the power of analytics capabilities, attrition rate has reduced by 40%. The estimated Total Operating Income impact of keeping all customers from churning is at an approxiamated of multi billion VND.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package for Analytics automation</title>
      <link>/project/r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/r-package/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working in BICC - VPBank, there are some common questions that a data science team has to solve:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could I find potential customers for a given product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does it look like the frequent patterns of customers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the retention rate/ cohort behaviour of customers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the customer behavior flows look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does one variable differ among various group?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and many other analytics questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve such problems, an R package named &lt;code&gt;VPBank&lt;/code&gt; has been created so as to release time for data analytics team. The package has helped Analytics team in many perspectives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce time to analyze data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardize many analytics process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unify template and format of graphics from different team members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the package, it has saved many working days for analytics team and make analytics process much shorter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Person Re-Identification System For Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/person-re-identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/person-re-identification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile visual clothing search</title>
      <link>/publication/clothing-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/clothing-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
