<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools | Anh Hoang Duc</title>
    <link>http://anhhoangduc.com/tag/tools/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://anhhoangduc.com/tag/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tools</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017 Anh Hoang Duc</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://anhhoangduc.com/images/icon_hu2b6525e60a3fd142ceb00d0e8ef368f7_181234_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>http://anhhoangduc.com/tag/tools/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package for Analytics automation</title>
      <link>http://anhhoangduc.com/project/r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://anhhoangduc.com/project/r-package/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working in BICC - VPBank, there are some common questions that a data science team has to solve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could I find potential customers for a given product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does it look like the frequent patterns of customers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the retention rate/ cohort behaviour of customers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the customer behavior flows look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does one variable differ among various group?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and many other analytics questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve such problems, we created an R package named &lt;code&gt;VPBank&lt;/code&gt; with 30+ built-in functions so as to release time for data analytics team. The package has helped Analytics team in many perspectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce time to analyze data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardize many analytics process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unify template and format of graphics from different team members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the package, it has saved many working days for analytics team and make analytics process much shorter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search engines for data terms</title>
      <link>http://anhhoangduc.com/project/search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://anhhoangduc.com/project/search-engine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building the new Data Warehouse, we have to deal with various data sources to extract business/data terms which will be use later for business.
However, we face some fundamental but challenging questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could I know that a term/multiple terms have been developed in the new DWH?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could I find data terms effectively as we face problems of Natural Language Processing with Vietnamese language?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve such problems, we built a search engine using &lt;code&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;Shiny&lt;/code&gt; in IBM Watson platform. The app help us to have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple but modern interface for business users to find data available in the new DWH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effectve search engine which can identify multiple terms with propensity of accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the app, it has saved hundreds hours for users/project to search and communicate to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL auto documentation</title>
      <link>http://anhhoangduc.com/project/sql-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://anhhoangduc.com/project/sql-document/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of daily jobs of a data analyst is to extract data from various sources in DWH to build a report for address business needs. 
However, when the number of data analysts as well as requests from business increase, there are some very difficult issues to solve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could a new data analyst can catch up quickly with the team?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could we separate business logics (usually as comments in SQL scripts) from SQL language so that the knowledge handover process can run smoothly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could we identify fundamental of SQL scripts, such as input tables, output tables and variables, steps to run the job without creating separate documents?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All theses three issues become harder to solve when the scale of the team increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve such problems, we build an &lt;code&gt;Shiny app&lt;/code&gt; which allows data analyst to upload a bundle of SQL scripts. The app will analyze and generate a beautiful HTML report which contains following information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input tables, output tables and variables used in all scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document auto-generated from comments from all scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the solution, data analytics boost productivity by at least 10% by eliminating all the cost of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
