<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Anh Hoang Duc</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Anh Hoang Duc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Anh Hoang Duc</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>About me My name is Anh Hoang Duc, a Business Analytics professional from Hanoi, Vietnam. I have a background in Quantitative Methods in Economics &amp;amp; am a co-founder of Ranalytics.vn, a group of data-addicted R users specializing in data analytics with the dream to bring the power of R &amp;amp; analytics to Vietnam. I am also an instructor of RStudio &amp;amp; Datacamp in Vietnam, providing various aspects of R such as data analysis, data wrangling, data vizualization or predictive modelling with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/projects/</guid>
      <description>Some selected interesting projects that I have done with my fantastic team</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I am teaching some R courses with Ranalytics:
 Data analysis with R - in Vietnamese Basic introduction to R in Vietnamese - Datacamp course  Recently, I have joined some conferences and workshops. During which, I am very happy to share my experience building analytics capabilities &amp;amp; implementations for attendees from different backgrounds.
 Human Resources Development Fund (HRDF) Conference, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia (19 Mar, 2018) Next BigTech Asia Conference/Workshop, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia (12-16 Mar, 2018) R users meetup - Experience sharing about Business Analytics (Mar, 2017)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny apps</title>
      <link>/home/shiny_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/shiny_app/</guid>
      <description>Apart from my work, I really enjoy my time to create shiny apps to automate some common analysis problems for my team, some of them are as follows:
 Market basket analysis Customers segmentation with RFM   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>