<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Anh Hoang Duc</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Anh Hoang Duc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Anh Hoang Duc</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Build recommendation engine for VPBank&#39;s customers</title>
      <link>/project/recommendation-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/recommendation-engine/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict credit card attritors</title>
      <link>/project/credit-card-attrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/credit-card-attrition/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-problem&#34;&gt;Business Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issueing credit cards is one of the main focuses of VPBank&amp;rsquo;s Retail Division, with a target of multi thousands new cards in 2017. However, there is little meaning in acquiring new card holders if they are going to churn in big numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, attrition rate was very high for newly issued cards, posing a substantial problem.
This calls for a need to identify potential attritors months before they make the action, enabling the Bank to take corrective measures to keep them from churning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The predictive problem belongs to the unbalanced classification category, one of the most difficult predictive models, with the monthly portion of attritors equalling to 2% of that of active cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final model was built using the &lt;strong&gt;Gradient Boosting Machine (GBM)&lt;/strong&gt; method after &lt;strong&gt;tuning multi hyper-parameters&lt;/strong&gt;.
As a combination between gradient descent and ada boost, GBM is a method of machine learning which combines many different decision trees to produce a powerful predictive model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also used data manipulation methods and activity analysis to find insightful findings within the transaction and card information datasets,
as well as build a customer profile that segments our customer base into 4 groups with distinctive between-group demographic and spending behaviors:
&lt;strong&gt;Attritors, High Risk Users, Typical Users and High Frequency Users&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;results-and-recommedations&#34;&gt;Results and Recommedations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilizing the model in conjuction with the customer profile, the Analytics team was able to provide the Products team with a list of almost &lt;strong&gt;12K potential attritors&lt;/strong&gt; and their respective card closing probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also made data-driven recommendations in regards of card policies, cross-selling programs and marketing campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementation-and-business-impact&#34;&gt;Implementation and Business Impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;implementation&#34;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list was provided for the Products team and is in use for a trial 3-month &amp;ldquo;Happy Call&amp;rdquo; Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also propose many target plan regarding customers&amp;rsquo; transacting behaviours
to maintain them with the bank, for instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The group of users that should be offered other product as the are misusing credit card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific number of tracsaction that each customers should have every one month &amp;amp; two months to make them to be loyal customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model is updated on quarterly basis to be able to detect credit card attritor more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;business-impact&#34;&gt;Business Impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After one year utilizing predictive modelling and the power of analytics capabilities, attrition rate has reduced by 40%. The estimated Total Operating Income impact of keeping all customers from churning is at an approxiamated of multi billion VND.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package for Analytics automation</title>
      <link>/project/example-external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/example-external-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-problems&#34;&gt;Business problems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working in BICC - VPBank, there are some common questions that a data science team has to solve:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could I find potential customers for a given product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does it look like the frequent patterns of customers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the retention rate/ cohort behaviour of customers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the customer behavior flows look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does one variable differ among various group?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and many other analytics questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve such problems, an R package named &lt;code&gt;VPBank&lt;/code&gt; has been created so as to release time for data analytics team. The package has helped Analytics team in many perspectives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce time to analyze data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardize many analytics process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unify template and format of graphics from different team members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the package, it has saved many working days for analytics team and make analytics process much shorter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
